A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Tech Women's Network, 1972-1991, undated
Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech
Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech
Records of the Virginia Tech Women's Network, 1972-1991, undated
Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
RG 30/7
4.2 Cubic Feet; 3 boxes
This collection includes information from the Women's Network at Virginia Tech from about 1973-1991. It includes letters, meeting minutes, reports, and more related to the operation of the organization as well as materials from different task forces and causes the Women's Network was backing.
Women's Network (Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University)
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research.
Source of Acquisition
The Records of the Virginia Tech Women's Network were transferred to Special Collections and University Archives in May 1989, October 1990, and January 2004.
Appraisal
The contents of Series I was received in binders. The binders were removed and destroyed. The contents were retained and placed in archival folders.
Administrative History
The Virginia Tech Women's Network was founded in 1977 within the College of Education, as a branch of the Virginia Women's Network. The goal of the group was to provide support for the university's professional women as well as advocate for an equal voice for women in the university.
Scope and Content
This collection contains records from the Women's Network at Virginia Tech, dated from about 1973 to 1991. It comprises correspondence, reports, publicity materials, and records related to the administration and the group's support of related causes.
Series I: Chronological files, 1973-1981, 1984-1991, contain records from the collection arranged by academic year, including letters, reports, meeting minutes, and more.
Series II: Publicity and Correspondence, 1978-1984, undated, consists of publicity materials, correspondence, letterhead, articles, newsletters, and "Women's Network News."
Series III: Causes, 1972-1973, 1975-1984, undated, contains information about different causes the Women's Network supported. This includes the Affirmative Action task force, the childcare task force, trying to get a class at Virginia Tech for Women's Studies, fighting for Women's Equity, preventing sexual harassment in the workforce, and more.
Series IV: Administration, 1980-1985, undated, is items related to the administrative side of the organization, such as a progress report, minutes for meetings, and ideas for the network.
Arrangement
This collection is separated into four series:
Series I: Chronological files, 1973-1981, 1984-1991
Series II: Publicity and Correspondence, 1978-1984, undated
Series III: Causes, 1972-1973, 1975-1984, undated
Series IV: Administration, 1980-1985, undated
Rights Statement for Archival Description
The guide to the Records of the Virginia Tech Women's Network by Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech, is licensed under a CC0 (https://creativecommons.org/share-your- work/public-domain/cc0/).
Index Terms
Subjects:
University Archives; University History; Women -- History
Organizations:
Women's Network (Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University); Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Contents List
- Series I: Chronological files, 1973-1981, 1984-1991
  - 1973-1981 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - 1985-05-1986-10 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1986-07-1987-04 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 5-7)
  - 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
  - 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
  - 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
  - 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 14-15)
- Series II: Publicity and Correspondence, 1978-1984, undated
  - Network Publicity (Newsletters, Coverage), 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Network Resources, 1978, 1980-1982 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Network Correspondence, 1980-1982 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Network - Correspondence with VT Administration, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Liaison - Staff Network, 1980, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Network and Liaison with Other Groups, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Spectrum Articles, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Letterhead, 1982-09-14, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Women's Network - Letterhead, 1983-1984, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - General Membership Lists and Memos, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Newsletter, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Newsletters and Network, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Newsletter, 1984, 1988, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Network - Public Relations/News General, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Old Women's Network News, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Women's Network News, Fall 1984 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Women's Network News, Fall 1985 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Women's Network News, Winter 1985 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Women's Network News, Fall 1986 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Women's Network News, Winter 1986 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Women's Network News--COPY, Winter 1986 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Women's Network Notes, 1984-1991 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Women's Network Paste-Ups/Blanks, 1984, 1986, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Other Women's Network News Items, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Network Mailing Lists and Membership, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Network Brochure Planning, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Series III: Causes, 1972-1973, 1975-1984, undated
  - Coalition, 1978, 1980-1982 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Network Policy/Task Forces, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Job Bank, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - College Personal Committees, 1981, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - University Child Care Task Force, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Child Care Task Force, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Child Care Task Force, 1982-1984 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Status of Affirmative Action Program and Appendices, 1975-1981 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Original of Task Force Report on Affirmative Action, 1978-1979, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Affirmative Action/Equal Employment Opportunity (AA/EEO), 1980-1982 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Affirmative Action Task Force, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Stuff from Patricia Hyer on Affirmative Action, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Network - Affirmative Action Task Force, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Women's Week Committee, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Women's Week, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Catharine Stimpon "Understanding Women: the State of the Art" Tape, 1982-05-07 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Catharine Stimpon, "Understanding Women", 1982-05-07 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Bibliography and Materials on Salary Equity Studies, 1972-1973, 1977, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Grievance Procedures and Women's Equity, 1982, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Sexual Harassment, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Perceptions of Sex Equity, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Salary Survey, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Final Draft - The Status of Women Faculty at VPISU, 1983-03-08 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Women's Studies Concentration, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Women's Studies, 1983-10-22 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Series IV: Administration, 1980-1985, undated
  - Network Administration, 1980-1983 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Network Minutes, 1980-1982 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Network Minutes and Letters, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Advisory Board, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Progress Report and Recommendations, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Other Women's Network Info, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Ideas for Network, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Elections for 1984-1985, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Sheets on Women's Records for Network, 1984, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Roanoke Network for Professional and Managerial Women Info, 1984-1985, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Women's Network Early History, 1977-1981, 1984-1985, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 26)